<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mental Health on Upskills</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/tags/mental-health/</link><description>Recent content in Mental Health on Upskills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>4 Science-based habits to build a highly productive brain| Jari Roomer</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/4-science-based-habits-to-build-a-highly-productive-brain-jari-roomer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/4-science-based-habits-to-build-a-highly-productive-brain-jari-roomer/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="4-science-based-habits-to-build-a-highly-productive-brain-jari-roomer"&gt;4 Science-based habits to build a highly productive brain| Jari Roomer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people reading this are - or will be - knowledge workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, they make money with their mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you make money with your mind, you&amp;rsquo;re a &lt;strong&gt;mental athlete.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Olympic athletes train their muscles, mental athletes should train their brains, as it can help with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster information processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced focus &amp;amp; mental clarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased mental efficiency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better decision-making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less brain fog &amp;amp; mental fatigue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, a healthy, high-performing brain gives you a competitive advantage in today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced knowledge economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s why, in this email, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over four science-based habits to build a faster, more productive brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="habit-1-manage-stress"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit #1: Manage Stress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chronic stress wreaks havoc on the brain and is linked to decreased gray matter in the prefrontal cortex - the area of the brain responsible for future planning, attention, and self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, prolonged exposure to stress can lead to chronic inflammation, which has been associated with cognitive decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to ensure a healthy and high-performing brain - and overall healthy life - it’s important to practice stress-reducing habits such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gratitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breathwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take time off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend time in nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="habit-2-prioritize-your-sleep"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit #2: Prioritize Your Sleep&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleep is “recovery mode” for the brain and is vital for better learning, memory, and cognitive function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During sleep, our brains actively work on repairing neural connections and flushing out toxins from our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This critical process helps to protect our brains from potential harm and ensures that we can function at our best when we&amp;rsquo;re awake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve the quality of your sleep, follow these tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your bedroom cool, dark, and quiet to create an optimal sleeping environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your devices away 1-2 hours before going to bed, as the blue light emitted from our screens disrupt the circadian rhythm and block melatonin production (an essential sleep hormone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t consume caffeine after 3 pm and avoid excessive sugar consumption in the evening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, getting good sleep (7-8 hours per night) is one of the best things you can do for better brain health and cognitive performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="habit-3-eat-brain-boosting-foods"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit #3: Eat Brain-Boosting Foods&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foods rich in &lt;strong&gt;high-quality fats&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the best brain boosters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As biohacker and brain expert Dave Asprey writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Fat is an essential nutrient for your brain. Eating the right kinds of fat can help you have more energy and think more clearly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best sources of high-quality fats are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avocados&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fish (wild-caught)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grass-fed butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key nutrient to improve our brain health and optimize cognitive performance is &lt;strong&gt;antioxidants&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antioxidants help reduce inflammation in the body and brain, which prevents cognitive decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foods rich in antioxidants are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Berries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spinach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brocolli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leafy greens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark chocolate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, make sure to eat a high-quality diet rich in brain-boosting nutrients such as healthy fats and antioxidants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="habit-4-exercise-often"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit #4: Exercise Often&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Studies show regular exercise (at least 3x a week) enhances cognitive performance and improves overall brain health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s because physical exercise boosts blood flow to the brain and increases the production of &lt;strong&gt;Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor (BDNF)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BDNF is an essential protein that promotes the health &amp;amp; growth of neurons in the brain, which is crucial for overall brain health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you want to boost your mental performance, make sure to exercise more often. Your brain will thank you for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To your productivity,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="references"&gt;References
&lt;/h4&gt;</description></item><item><title>(Non-Sleep Deep Rest) with Dr. Andrew Huberman</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/non-sleep-deep-rest-with-dr.-andrew-huberman/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/non-sleep-deep-rest-with-dr.-andrew-huberman/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="non-sleep-deep-rest-with-dr-andrew-huberman"&gt;(Non-Sleep Deep Rest) with Dr. Andrew Huberman
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AKGrmY8OSHM"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>