<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Upskills</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Upskills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Monk Mode: An extreme (but effective) 30-day protocol to become your most productive self | Jari Roomer</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/monk-mode-an-extreme-but-effective-30-day-protocol-to-become-your-most-productive-self-jari-roomer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/monk-mode-an-extreme-but-effective-30-day-protocol-to-become-your-most-productive-self-jari-roomer/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="monk-mode-an-extreme-but-effective-30-day-protocol-to-become-your-most-productive-self"&gt;Monk Mode: An extreme (but effective) 30-day protocol to become your most productive self
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monk mode is a period of full focus and commitment to one goal or project - usually between 14 to 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, you block out distractions, limit obligations, and put yourself in peak performance mode, so you can make leaps of progress on a goal or project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to practice monk mode three to four times a year, with each monk mode being 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During 30 days of monk mode, I can get done what I’d normally do in 90 ‘ordinary’ days. That’s how powerful it can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, monk mode is not for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s quite intense, requires planning, and involves making sacrifices (in your social life, delaying gratification, being strict with yourself, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if it speaks to you, keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-rules-of-monk-mode"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rules of Monk Mode&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many different monk mode protocols out there - each with different rules and practices - but here’s how I approach monk mode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="limit-social-media-to-20-minutes-a-day"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limit Social Media To 20 Minutes A Day&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social media is one of the biggest distractions and time-wasters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average person spends &lt;a class="link" href="https://click.convertkit-mail2.com/k0uk9k42kof2ux38evtlho7ed277f8/48hvhehrekgldwtx/aHR0cHM6Ly90ZWNoanVyeS5uZXQvYmxvZy90aW1lLXNwZW50LW9uLXNvY2lhbC1tZWRpYS8=" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;2 hours and 31 minutes&lt;/a&gt; per day on social media, while young adults (age 18-29) spend an average of &lt;a class="link" href="https://click.convertkit-mail2.com/k0uk9k42kof2ux38evtlho7ed277f8/wnh2hghwp8g72nc7/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubnl0aW1lcy5jb20vMjAyMi8wMy8yNC93ZWxsL2ZhbWlseS9jaGlsZC1zb2NpYWwtbWVkaWEtdXNlLmh0bWw=" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;4-5 hours per day&lt;/a&gt; on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why one of my core rules of monk mode is to limit my social media usage to 20 minutes per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This frees up a good amount of time, focus, and headspace to direct toward my main goal for that specific monk mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I use &lt;a class="link" href="https://click.convertkit-mail2.com/k0uk9k42kof2ux38evtlho7ed277f8/reh8hoh0rnxdldh2/aHR0cHM6Ly9hcHBibG9jay5hcHAv" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;App Block&lt;/a&gt; to put a daily time limit on Instagram and X, which automatically blocks me from using these apps when I reach the usage limit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most social media apps and platforms have been purposefully designed to hack your attention and be as addictive as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a financial incentive to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more time you spend on social media, the more ad revenue these social media companies make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often think social media is free, but it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You pay with your time and your attention. &lt;strong&gt;Your attention is their business model.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During monk mode, you can’t afford to waste your time and attention on a distraction like social media, so you have to limit it (or cut it out).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="no-porn--masturbation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Porn &amp;amp; Masturbation&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Watching porn overstimulates the brain’s reward system, leaving you feeling lethargic, lazy, and unmotivated to do anything productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s cheap dopamine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, avoid porn and masturbation during your monk mode to preserve your energy and motivation for your main goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="90-minutes-of-deep-work-3-4x-a-day"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;90-Minutes Of Deep Work 3-4x A Day&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Focus is the currency of productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can’t focus, you can’t produce high-quality output. And if you can’t produce high-quality output, you can’t succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why &lt;strong&gt;deep work forms the core of my monk modes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s during deep work that you actually get stuff done and make progress on your main objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To maximize your deep work sessions, make sure you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn notifications off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your phone out of sight (and out of reach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close all unrelated internet tabs (especially social media, email &amp;amp; news)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put on noise-canceling headphones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to binaural beats or LoFi beats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick one high-priority task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a timer for 60-90 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work without interruption until the timer rings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that each hour spent in deep work equals the output of three ‘normal’ work hours, that’s how powerful it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During monk mode, I like to do three to four deep work sessions per day, with each session being 90 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On the weekends I usually do 2x 90-minute deep work sessions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I schedule most of my deep work sessions for the morning hours, as that’s when I’m naturally most energized, focused, and productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7-hours-of-sleep-a-night"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7+ Hours of Sleep A Night&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During monk mode, I’m in bed by 22:30 and up by 7:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a non-negotiable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s because a good night’s sleep (7+ hours) is the foundation of a highly productive day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you don’t prioritize rest and recovery, you can’t perform at your best the next day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​&lt;a class="link" href="https://click.convertkit-mail2.com/k0uk9k42kof2ux38evtlho7ed277f8/08hwh9hd5qze6rul/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubmNiaS5ubG0ubmloLmdvdi9wbWMvYXJ0aWNsZXMvUE1DNjE0MzM0Ni8=" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt; has shown that we’re more prone to distractions, brain fog, and instant gratification after a bad night’s sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you want to operate at peak productivity, prioritize your sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="limit-meetings--social-events"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limit Meetings &amp;amp; Social Events&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During monk mode, I’m more mindful of how many meetings I schedule and how many social events I attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not like I’m skipping everything, but I’m simply more selective of how (and with whom) I spend my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you say yes to every social event or ‘let’s hop on a quick call’ request, you’ll have less time and energy for your main monk mode objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="no-alcohol"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Alcohol&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although I enjoy the occasional beer or two with my friends, alcohol is a no-go during monk mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with alcohol is that you borrow energy from tomorrow’s self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be a lot of fun in the moment, but you’re going to pay the bill the day after in the form of fatigue, headaches, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, no alcohol during monk mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preserve your energy and mental clarity for your main goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="try-out-monk-mode-yourself"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try Out Monk Mode Yourself&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monk mode is one of those things you can read about, but there’s really no point if you don’t try it out yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to follow my approach to monk mode, or consider adding some other rules or habits to your monk mode protocol, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No TV/Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No news&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No video games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily journaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditate 10-minutes a day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read 15 pages a day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat organic foods only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise 30-minutes a day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, monk mode is an intense but highly effective method to make leaps of progress on a goal or project in just 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it interests you, give it a shot. I can highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To your productivity,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="references"&gt;References
&lt;/h4&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ramit's Brain Trust Insights | Ramit Sethi</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/ramits-brain-trust-insights-ramit-sethi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/ramits-brain-trust-insights-ramit-sethi/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="ramit-by-ramit-sethi"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.iwillteachyoutoberich.com/ramits-brain-trust-insights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ramit&amp;rsquo;s Brain Trust Insights&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="link" href="https://twitter.com/ramit" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ramit Sethi&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This brain trust provides access to knowledge, wisdom and proven strategies that top performers uses in business, psychology, finance, marketing, and entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PLPZCUlZ2z01kZ4dAg5IgWLB0ffDoHCjVi"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copied content from &lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/@ryanstephens/24-things-i-learned-in-the-first-year-of-ramit-s-brain-trust-5d12c577c7df" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;24 Things I Learned in the First Year of Ramit’s Brain Trust&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="link" href="https://twitter.com/ryanstephens" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ryan Stephens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November of 2012 I decided to join &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.iwillteachyoutoberich.com/braintrust/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;professional network/entrepreneurial brain trust&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rationale was simple, &lt;strong&gt;successful people don’t succeed on their own&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two parts to the program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monthly interviews with a wide array of brilliant people, masters and advisors that have helped countless people with productivity, health, psychology, and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Membership to an exclusive community of ambitious professionals to hold you accountable, encourage you, and help you live a Rich Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/book-reviews/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;as much&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/@ryanstephens/my-favorite-reads-for-2015-b498df3261c9#.no2aa8t4v" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;or more&lt;/a&gt;) than anyone I know (sans &lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/2e2701ae378f?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ryan Holiday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/4e1546c1a1a1?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;), but reading is a time consuming endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brain trust provides access to knowledge, wisdom and proven strategies that top performers use to…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get more done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay focused&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earn more money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are 24 of my favorite takeaways from my first year as a participant in &lt;a class="link" href="http://braintrust.iwtstudents.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ramit’s Brain Trust&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3 id="james-altucher"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/cac1bc5422de?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;James Altucher&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="1-build-your-life-around-themes-not-goals"&gt;1.) Build Your Life Around Themes, Not Goals
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals focus on outcomes, themes on the process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals = Not satisfied with where you are. You achieve it once and then not satisfied anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Themes = “I want to provide value that will reward me financially.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott Adams, the author of Dilbert, has some &lt;a class="link" href="http://blog.dilbert.com/post/102964992706/goals-vs-systems" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;great thoughts on goals vs. systems&lt;/a&gt;. So does &lt;a class="link" href="http://jamesclear.com/goals-systems" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;James Clear&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a class="link" href="http://alearningaday.com/2015/07/goals-vs-systems-and-its-implications-on-management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Rohan Rajiv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="2-build-your-list-but-also-connect-your-list"&gt;2.) Build Your List, But Also Connect Your List
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you introduce two people who hit it off, you’re the meta connector, the common factor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They will always remember you and you’ll always be on their mind for future potential connections they can make that would be useful for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce two people with an idea in mind. If you can help two other people make money then eventually, good things will happen to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/james_altucher/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to deal with your fear of failure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3 id="charles-duhigg"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/88f84fcb3bf4?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Charles Duhigg&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="3-the-power-of-habit"&gt;3.) The Power of Habit
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human willpower is limited; it gets depleted over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like a muscle, you can strengthen it by using it more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should try to change behaviors into habits (e.g brushing your teeth is easy because it’s a habit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing good keystone habits (exercising, financial discipline, etc.) creates chain reactions — permeating other areas of your life and changing and rearranging your other habits as you integrate the (keystone) habit into your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="4-the-three-parts-of-a-habit"&gt;4.) The Three Parts of a Habit
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:700/1*lUDRKIoyPXd3rtmKzr3Ghg.png"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cues (starts behavior)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routine (behavior itself)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewards (how brain learns to encode for the future)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/charles-duhigg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about the power of habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3 id="rob-kelly"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/90fa6ef7778d?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Rob Kelly&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="5-create-a-qualities-of-achievement-document"&gt;5.) Create a Qualities of Achievement Document
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a simple way to increase your confidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This should be a blueprint to achieve future success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about how to create your own &lt;a class="link" href="http://robdkelly.com/blog/personal-development/confidence-building-exercise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="6-turn-ideas-into-reality"&gt;6.) Turn Ideas into Reality
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage your competencies. What are you really good at? What do you love doing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit your content about the topic into the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a feedback loop, measure what is going on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This echoes Austin Kleon’s &lt;a class="link" href="http://austinkleon.com/2016/03/24/3-reasons-why-you-should-show-your-work/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;3 reasons you should show your work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/rob_kelly/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to find your purpose in life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="chris-yeh"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/962d67bbf4ad?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Chris Yeh&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="7-networking-is-not-transactional"&gt;7.) Networking is Not Transactional
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone is smart/interesting, take the time to meet with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is about relationships. Meet with smart people and stay in touch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calling people keeps you top of mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to people –&amp;gt; Find out where there’s a need –&amp;gt; Prove you can fill that need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="8-the-architecture-of-top-performers"&gt;8.) The Architecture of Top Performers
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s your foundation? It needs to be sturdy so you can build on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your non-negotiables that have to take precedence? Things like your family. What other non-negotiables need to be in place to ensure you’re doing your best work? (Exercise, Sleep, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:518/0*1IQXRKObKk7TPSXP.png"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/chris-yeh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to think like top performers and leaders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="bj-fogg"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/fb268ac5c474?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;BJ Fogg&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="9-create-tiny-habits-and-eliminate-barriers-to-inefficiency"&gt;9.) Create Tiny Habits and Eliminate Barriers to Inefficiency
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design for laziness (e.g if there’s a full water bottle on your desk at all times you’ll drink more water)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incremental improvements are more reliable and robust for long-term behavior change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="10-do-hard-things-now-to-make-future-things-easy"&gt;10.) Do Hard Things Now to Make Future Things Easy
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation only has one role in our lives and that’s to help us to do hard things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a system to make it easy even with low motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:539/0*hlDYJ5kcDyl7ew38.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A great example would be to prepare all your meals for the week in individual Tupperware on Sunday when you have energy so that during your (busy) work week, when your motivation to eat healthy is low, you can just grab your food and heat it up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/bj_fogg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to get out of a rut and find the motivation to change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ben-casnocha"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/b6704f2a323b?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ben Casnocha&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="11-career-plans-limit-your-options-in-todays-world"&gt;11.) Career Plans Limit Your Options in Today’s World
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sheryl Sandberg says, “I don’t have a career plan”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 things to keep in mind when thinking about your career:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:556/0*LdgwTXhEUbquLYPX.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="12when-making-important-decisions-use-the-regret-minimization-framework"&gt;12.)When Making Important Decisions, Use the Regret Minimization Framework
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:536/0*quG7fCHg5Gcy2CGe.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly I made up a new word, “minimalization” in my commonplace book notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s &lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/evaluating-tough-decisions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;5 Ways to Evaluate Tough Career Decisions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s the Heath brothers &lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/how-to-make-better-choices-in-life-and-work/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;four-step process&lt;/a&gt; designed to counteract the array of biases and irrationality that disrupt our decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/ben-casnocha/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how career builders choose the right path&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gretchen-rubin"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/591753f73a84?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Gretchen Rubin&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="13-youre-probably-happier-than-you-think"&gt;13.) You’re Probably Happier Than You Think
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step to greater happiness is to acknowledge how happy you are now, then deliberately think about what makes you happy to add more of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way I’ve (personally) found to do this is to start a gratitude journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:700/0*4Q9ru5p1ykmvf5Sa.png"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.bakadesuyo.com/2015/05/happy-all-the-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Here’s four rituals to keep you happy all the time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="14-negative-emotions-play-an-important-role-in-happiness"&gt;14.) Negative Emotions Play an Important Role in Happiness
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have strong self-knowledge, negative emotions provide signals of things you need to change in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whom do you envy? Why? (e.g. I envy writers because they have more flexibility to work from home; therefore, I’m going to try and shift my work priorities to work from home more often to increase my happiness)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make things you envy a priority to obtain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What steps can you take to make that happen for you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you lie about?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re uncomfortable telling the truth, perhaps there are steps you need to take to change (e.g. you tell everyone you moved closer to work so you could walk, but you still drive in everyday)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/gretchen-rubin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to be happy for life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="michael-ellsberg"&gt;Michael Ellsberg
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="15-your-level-of-success-is-dependent-on-how-open-you-are-to-feedback"&gt;15.) Your Level of Success is Dependent on How Open you are to Feedback
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s not about you (personally); it’s about your performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actively solicit how you come across to others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When asking for feedback, tell others/your boss, “I want your hardest shot and I won’t be offended”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="16-a-network-of-relationships-is-essentially-a-network-of-trust"&gt;16.) A Network of Relationships is Essentially a Network of Trust
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act in a way that a large number of people will trust you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proactively suggest some ways to help those in your network; be very specific&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes busy people are busy (take a long-term approach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust is currency. It reduces &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;cost&lt;/strong&gt; of doing transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your brain needs diversity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/michael-ellsberg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to network and invest in yourself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3 id="ron-lieber"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/fcbbd64696d5?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ron Lieber&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="17-its-imperative-to-understand-the-strategies-and-tactics-required-to-elevate-your-career"&gt;17.) It’s Imperative to Understand the Strategies and Tactics Required to Elevate Your Career
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the time to study the people who came before you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on people’s biggest pain points and/or their largest expense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with original answers for old questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make complicated things “make sense”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be conversational: Start at the beginning/from scratch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help relatively smart people understand something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for emerging areas of interest (cast a wide/eclectic net)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stunt + aspirational + useful + service to people = success (e.g Julia Child’s recipes blogged by Julie Powell)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with your obsessions, then move at half steps to find your beat or niche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="18-a-great-way-to-build-instant-rapport-is-to-write-smart-thoughtful-dashes"&gt;18.) A Great Way to Build Instant Rapport is to Write Smart, Thoughtful Dashes
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send notes letting people know what you like and/or admire about their work; be very specific and detailed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example: “Hey I read your thing and I liked/noticed/appreciated…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/ron-lieber/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to build instant rapport and make it to the top of your field&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3 id="chris-guillebeau"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/e34c8275921a?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Chris Guillebeau&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="19-4-ways-to-manage-criticism"&gt;19.) 4 Ways to Manage Criticism
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize the struggle around focusing on the one negative comment amidst many compliments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize that criticism is often a project of the giver. It might have nothing to do you with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the time to step away, then separate the point from the emotion. There might be truth to the criticism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopt a long-term focus. Critics are interested in battles; whereas, you want to win the war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="20-3-keys-to-achieving-your-goals"&gt;20.) 3 Keys to Achieving Your Goals
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with internal motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then add public accountability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be consistent and persistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/chris-guillebeau/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about how to set goals, crush them, and live a better life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3 id="josh-kaufman"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/4442b307d189?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Josh Kaufman&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="21-how-to-acquire-a-skill-rapidly"&gt;21.) How to Acquire a Skill Rapidly
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 hours is the critical threshold of practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deconstruction: Break down the skill. What equipment? What micro skills? (Consider &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.4hourlife.com/2013/02/11/how-to-use-the-4-hour-chef-and-disss-to-tackle-and-conquer-any-problem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Tim Ferriss’ DiSSS method&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn just enough theory to (self) skill correct. Less research, more practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove practice barriers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice, not research, for 20 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="22-how-and-why-you-should-systematize-your-life"&gt;22.) How and Why You Should Systematize Your Life
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you spend more than 5 hours/week on something, you should create a system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do it once. Do your best. Document it. Systematize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A system is a repeatable process with repeatable results. Awareness and flexibility to tweak processes and get results. Makes it easier to diagnose problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example: Hiring a housekeeper. Washing dishes = X amount of time (repeatable), but what if we used that time to write a blog post? (lasts forever)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/josh-kaufman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about acquiring any skill rapidly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=""&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3 id="pamela-slim"&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://medium.com/u/b523d2b138a1?source=post_page-----5d12c577c7df--------------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Pamela Slim&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="23-how-to-be-invaluable-at-your-job"&gt;23.) How to Be Invaluable at Your Job
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be hyper-aware of market dynamics, not just trends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think of your boss as a client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be in charge of how you maintain employability and generate revenue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure you’re in a position aligned with your natural strengths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study your craft inside and outside of your company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearly define the people you want to emulate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get very specific, clear feedback (and learn how to take it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="24-dont-undervalue-yourself"&gt;24.) &lt;strong&gt;Don’t Undervalue Yourself:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You MUST charge what the market will bear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think it’s “too much,” invest it back into yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use it to increase your influence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use it to buy your time back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or just give it to charity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://ryanstephensmarketing.com/blog/pam-slim/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Learn more about becoming invaluable at your job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taking Book Notes (How to Start) | Alex</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/taking-book-notes-how-to-start-alex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/taking-book-notes-how-to-start-alex/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="whats-the-best-way-to-turn-any-book-into-a-second-brain-of-insights-that-you-can-grab-off-the-shelf-at-any-time--alex"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to turn any book into a Second Brain of insights that you can grab off the shelf at any time? | Alex
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fES9ZrLXY9s"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>10 Productivity tips and tricks that work | Ankur Warikoo</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/10-productivity-tips-and-tricks-that-work-ankur-warikoo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/10-productivity-tips-and-tricks-that-work-ankur-warikoo/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="10-productivity-tips-and-tricks-that-work--ankur-warikoo"&gt;10 Productivity tips and tricks that work | Ankur Warikoo
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not try to remember anything, document everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I document everything, ideas, to-do list, meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put everything on the calendar. I use the calendar to - block my time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I schedule emails to myself and receive them in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use technology for everything I can. X.ai(calendar scheduling tool), boomerang(for Gmail).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share your calendar with people close to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making Whatsapp self-group. One for images and videos, the other for ideas and thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Afternoon nap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting the right environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing things that activate your senses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U0gvKt7TKic"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>10 small changes that will improve your life | Matt D'Avella</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/10-small-changes-that-will-improve-your-life-matt-davella/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/10-small-changes-that-will-improve-your-life-matt-davella/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="heres-the-list-which-one-do-you-want-to-work-on-next"&gt;Here’s the list. Which one do you want to work on next?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you set your alarm before bed, put it on the other side of the bedroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one personal item to your work to-do list each day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep a “Praise” folder in your email inbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carry a water bottle with you everywhere you go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t go to sleep angry at the people you care about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invest in quality, non-processed, organic food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit the junk food you bring into your house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave your phone on silent and upside down at all times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write out a physical to-do list before you go to bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take at least ten minutes each day to be still.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wIIGCTIpRMk"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>Goals vs. Systems</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/goals-vs.-systems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/goals-vs.-systems/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="goals-vs-systems"&gt;Goals vs. Systems
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fwcKTYvupJw"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Best Productivity Hacks of All Time</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/the-best-productivity-hacks-of-all-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/the-best-productivity-hacks-of-all-time/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="productivity-hacks"&gt;Productivity Hacks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delegating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The two minute rule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The two day rule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time blocking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The five minute rule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily highlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color coding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-do lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consuming content at 2x speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadlines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eisenhower Matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoying the journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4aYVLpY5FYU"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to sleep productively</title><link>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/how-to-sleep-productively/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://prasenjitmanna.com/upskills/p/how-to-sleep-productively/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sleep-facts"&gt;Sleep Facts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An afternoon nap increases the brain&amp;rsquo;s learning capacity by 15-20%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep improves your memory, halting forgetting by 30-50%, relative to staying awake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not getting enough sleep increases sweet and salty cravings by 30-40%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep offers a three-fold bost in creativity and problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep improves time to physical exhaustion when exercising by 10-30%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="video-wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Oq4c-_iAzQo"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>